retailtouchpoints.com 2019-04-11

# Privacy Policy - Retail TouchPoints

**Version:** 2.0 _([view v1.0](http://retailtouchpoints.com/general/privacy-policy-v1))_  
 **Updated:** May 24, 2018

* * *

**Retail TouchPoints** ("us," "we," or "our") operates the [http://retailtouchpoints.com](http://retailtouchpoints.com/) website (the "Service").

This page informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of personal data when you use our Service and the choices you have associated with that data.

We use your data to provide and improve the Service. By using the Service, you agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy.

* * *

##  Definitions

####    
Personal Data

Personal Data means data about a living individual who can be identified from that data (or from that and other information either in our possession or likely to come into our possession).

#### User

The User is the individual using our Service. The User corresponds to the Data Subject, who is the subject of Personal Data.

#### Usage Data

Usage Data is data collected automatically, either generated by the use of the Service or from the Service infrastructure itself (for example, the duration of a page visit).

#### Cookies

Cookies are small pieces of data stored on a User’s device.[  
](https://www.retailtouchpoints.com/general/pages/privacy-policy#_msocom_1)

#### Data Controller

Data Controller means a person who (either alone, jointly, or in common with other persons) determines the purposes for which, and the manner in which any personal data are, or are to be, processed.

For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, we are a Data Controller of your data.

#### Data Processor (or Service Providers)

Data Processor (or Service Provider) means any person (other than an employee of the Data Controller) who processes the data on behalf of the Data Controller.

We may use the services of various Service Providers in order to process, optimize, or store your data for our Service.

#### Data Subject

Data Subject is any living individual who is the subject of Personal Data.

* * *

##  Information Collection And Use

We collect several different types of information for various purposes to provide and improve our Service to you. Below you'll find the types of data we collect.

#### Personal Data

While using our Service, we may ask you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information that can be used to contact or identify you ("Personal Data"). Personally identifiable information may include, but is not limited to:

  * Email address
  * First name and last name
  * Phone number
  * Address, State, Province, ZIP/Postal code, City
  * Company Information (Name, address, size, revenue, and other)
  * Content interests
  * Cookies and Usage Data

We may use your Personal Data to contact you with newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other information that may be of interest to you. You may opt out of receiving any or all of these communications from us by following the unsubscribe link or instructions provided in any email we send or by contacting us.

#### Usage Data

We may also collect information on how you access and use our website and Services ("Usage Data"). This Usage Data may include information such as your computer's Internet Protocol address (e.g. IP address), browser type, browser version, the pages of our website/services that you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages, unique device identifiers and other diagnostic data.

#### Location Data

We may use and store information about your location if you give us permission to do so (“Location Data”). We use this data to provide features of our Service, and to improve and customize our Service.

You can enable or disable location services when you use our Service at any time through your device settings.

#### Tracking Cookies Data

We use cookies and similar tracking technologies to track the activity on our Service and hold certain information.

Cookies are files with small amounts of data that may include an anonymous unique identifier. Cookies are sent to your browser from a website and stored on your device. Tracking technologies also used are beacons, tags, and scripts to collect and track information and to improve and analyze our Service.

You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of our Service.

Examples of Cookies we use:

  * **Session Cookies:** We use Session Cookies to operate our Service.
  * **Preference Cookies:** We use Preference Cookies to remember your preferences, interest and various settings.
  * **Security Cookies:** We use Security Cookies for security purposes.
  * **Advertising Cookies:** Advertising Cookies are used to serve you with advertisements that may be relevant to you and your interests.

* * *

## Use Of Data

Retail TouchPoints uses the collected data for various purposes:

  * To provide and maintain our Service
  * To notify you about changes to our Service
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of our Service when you choose to do so
  * To provide customer support
  * To gather analysis or valuable information so that we can improve our Service
  * To monitor the usage of our Service
  * To detect, prevent and address technical issues
  * To provide you with news, special offers and general information about other goods, services and events that we offer, which are similar to those that you have already purchased or enquired about unless you have opted not to receive such information
  * To provide our partners or sponsors the specific content you had downloaded, subscribed to, registered for, or inquired about. 

* * *

## Retention of Data

Retail TouchPoints will retain your Personal Data only for as long as it is necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. We will retain and use your Personal Data to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations (for example, if we are required to retain your data to comply with applicable laws), resolve disputes, and enforce our legal agreements and policies.

Retail TouchPoints will also retain Usage Data for internal analysis purposes. Usage Data is generally retained for a shorter period of time, except when the data is used to strengthen the security or to improve the functionality of our service and offering, or we are legally obligated to retain this data for longer time periods.

* * *

##  Transfer Of Data

Your information, including Personal Data, may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction.

If you are located outside the United States and choose to provide information to us, please note that we transfer the data, including Personal Data, to the United States and process it there.

Your information may be transferred and distributed to our partners or direct sponsors of the content you have downloaded, registered for, subscribed to, or inquired about.

Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

Retail TouchPoints will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and no transfer of your Personal Data will take place to an organization or a country unless there are adequate controls in place regarding the security of your data and other personal information.

* * *

##  Disclosure Of Data

####    
Legal Requirements

Retail TouchPoints may disclose your Personal Data in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to:

  * Comply with a legal obligation
  * Protect and defend the rights or property of Retail TouchPoints
  * Prevent or investigate possible wrongdoing in connection with the Service
  * Protect the personal safety of users of the Service or the public
  * Protect against legal liability

* * *

## Security Of Data

The security of your data is important to us, but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Data, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

* * *

## "Do Not Track" Signals

We do not support Do Not Track ("DNT"). Do Not Track is a preference you can set in your web browser to inform websites that you do not want to be tracked.

You can enable or disable Do Not Track by visiting the Preferences or Settings page of your web browser.

* * *

##  Your Rights

Retail TouchPoints aims to take reasonable steps to allow you to correct, amend, delete, or limit the use of your Personal Data.

Whenever made possible, you can update your Personal Data directly by updating your profile. If you are unable to change your Personal Data, please contact us to make the required changes.

If you wish to be informed what Personal Data we hold about you and if you want it to be removed from our systems, please contact us.

In certain circumstances, you have the right to:

  * Access and receive a copy of the Personal Data we hold about you
  * Rectify any Personal Data held about you that is inaccurate
  * Request the deletion of Personal Data held about you

You have the right to data portability for the information you provide to Retail TouchPoints. You can request to obtain a copy of your Personal Data in a commonly used electronic format so that you can manage and move it.

Please note that we may ask you to verify your identity before responding to such requests.

* * *

##  Service Providers

We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service ("Service Providers"), to provide the Service on our behalf, to perform Service-related services or to assist us in analyzing how our Service is used.

These third parties have access to your Personal Data only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.

#### Marketing Automation & Database

We may use third-party Service Providers to collect, monitor, analyze, and execute marketing campaigns for our Service.

**Marketo  
** Marketo is a marketing automation platform focused on account-based marketing, including email, mobile, social, digital ads, web management and analytics. It has customized solutions for different industries including healthcare, technology, financial services, manufacturing, media and higher education. For more information on their privacy practices, please visit the Marketo Privacy Notice web page: <https://documents.marketo.com/legal/privacy/>

**Mautic**  
Mautic is an open-source marketing automation tool. It enables brands to integrate and personalize their digital properties and channels into a seamless customer experience. For more information on the privacy practices of Mautic, please visit their privacy policy web page: <https://mautic.com/privacy-policy/>

**On24**  
ON24 is a webinar-based marketing solution that helps drive demand generation and customer engagement. Its cloud-based platform features an interactive and immersive user interface, and industry-leading webinar analytics for events, campaigns and benchmarking. For more information on the privacy practices of On24, please visit their privacy policy web page: <https://www.on24.com/about-us/privacy-policy/>[](https://www.on24.com/about-us/privacy-policy/)

#### Analytics

We may use third-party Service Providers to monitor and analyze the use of our Service.

**Google Analytics  
** Google Analytics is a web analytics service offered by Google that tracks and reports website traffic. Google uses the data collected to track and monitor the use of our Service. This data is shared with other Google services. Google may use the collected data to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network. You can opt-out of having made your activity on the Service available to Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. The add-on prevents the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js, analytics.js, and dc.js) from sharing information with Google Analytics about visits activity. For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy Terms web page: <http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>

#### Advertising

We may use third-party Service Providers to show advertisements to you to help support and maintain our Service.

**Google AdSense DoubleClick  
** Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our Service. Google's use of the DoubleClick cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to our users based on their visit to our Service or other websites on the Internet. You may opt out of the use of the DoubleClick Cookie for interest-based advertising by visiting the Google Ads Settings web page: <http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/> 

#### Behavioral Remarketing

Retail TouchPoints uses remarketing services to advertise to you on third-party websites after you visit our Service. We and our third-party vendors use cookies to inform, optimize and serve ads based on your past visits to our Service.

**Google AdWords**  
Google AdWords remarketing service is provided by Google Inc. You can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize the Google Display Network ads by visiting the Google Ads Settings page: <http://www.google.com/settings/ads>. Google also recommends installing the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on — <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout> — for your web browser. Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on provides visitors with the ability to prevent their data from being collected and used by Google Analytics. For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy Terms web page: <http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>

**Twitter**  
Twitter remarketing service is provided by Twitter Inc. You can opt-out from Twitter's interest-based ads by following their instructions: <https://support.twitter.com/articles/20170405>. You can learn more about the privacy practices and policies of Twitter by visiting their Privacy Policy page: <https://twitter.com/privacy>

**Facebook**  
Facebook remarketing service is provided by Facebook Inc. You can learn more about interest-based advertising from Facebook by visiting this page: <https://www.facebook.com/help/164968693837950>. To opt-out from Facebook's interest-based ads, follow these instructions from Facebook: <https://www.facebook.com/help/568137493302217>. Facebook adheres to the Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising established by the Digital Advertising Alliance. You can also opt-out from Facebook and other participating companies through the Digital Advertising Alliance in the USA (<http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>), the Digital Advertising Alliance of Canada in Canada (<http://youradchoices.ca/>) or the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance in Europe (<http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/>), or opt-out using your mobile device settings. For more information on the privacy practices of Facebook, please visit Facebook's Data Policy: <https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation>

**AdRoll**  
AdRoll remarketing service is provided by Semantic Sugar, Inc. You can opt-out of AdRoll remarketing by visiting this AdRoll Advertising Preferences web page: [http://info.evidon.com/pub_info/573?v=1nt=1nw=false](http://info.evidon.com/pub_info/573?v=1&nt=1&nw=false). For more information on the privacy practices of AdRoll, please visit the AdRoll Privacy Policy web page: <http://www.adroll.com/about/privacy>

**Bombora**  
Bombora uses B2B demographic, firmographic, and intent data to tailor ads for our subscribers across the web. You can opt-out of Bombora ads and data collection by visiting this page: <https://bombora.com/opt-out/>. For more information on privacy practices of Bombora, please visit the Bombora Privacy Policy web page: <https://bombora.com/privacy/>

#### Marketing Partners

We may use third-party Service Providers to help generate interest in our content for our visitors and sponsors.

**Pangea Global Services**  
Pangea Global Services provides market research, data analytics, lead generation, among many other services. Please visit Pangea Global Services’ Privacy Policy web page: <https://www.pangeaglobalservices.com/Privacy_policy.html>[](https://www.pangeaglobalservices.com/Privacy_policy.html)  

* * *

## Links To Other Sites

Our Service may contain links to other sites that are not operated by us. If you click on a third-party link, you will be directed to that third party's site. We strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of every site you visit.

We have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third-party sites or services.

* * *

## Children's Privacy

Our Service does not address anyone under the age of 13 ("Children").

We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your Children have provided us with Personal Data, please contact us. If we become aware that we have collected Personal Data from children without verification of parental consent, we take steps to remove that information from our servers.

* * *

## Changes To This Privacy Policy

We may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page.

We will let you know via email and/or a prominent notice on our Service prior to the change becoming effective and will update the "effective date" at the top of this Privacy Policy.

You are advised to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

* * *

## Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us:

  * By email: **info@retailtouchpoints.com**
  * By phone number: **1-201-257-8528**
  * By mail: 777 Terrace Ave, Suite 202, Hasbrouck Heights, NJ 07604, USA
